hyperxgaming.com 2017-09-11

# Privacy Statement | Kingston

##### PRIVACY STATEMENT

Kingston is a global organization comprising of a group of entities affiliated with, controlled by or under common control with Kingston Technology Company, Inc. Accordingly references in this Privacy Policy and elsewhere on this website to ‘Kingston,’ ‘our,’ ‘we’ or ‘us’ mean Kingston Technology Company, Inc. and entities affiliated with, controlled by or under common control with it, as the context so requires. This Privacy Policy applies to all information, including personal information, collected about you by Kingston.

At Kingston we know that protecting your privacy is important. We’ve written this Privacy Policy to explain:

  * When we collect information

  * What type of information we collect

  * How we collect information

  * How we use information

  * With whom we share information

  * The steps we take to protect your information.

##### WHEN DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION?

Kingston may collect information about you when you interact with us in the following ways:

  * Access or browse one of our Websites

  * Order Kingston products or services

  * Communicate with us via e-mail, telephone, fax or other manner

  * Register your Kingston product or fill out a survey

  * Elect to participate in a Kingston promotion, including but not limited to rebates, contests, etc.

  * Request or register to receive information about our products or services

  * Meet face to face or hand over your business card at a trade show, exhibition, corporate event, meeting, conference, PR event, training or technology seminar or any other event

##### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

Information we collect is generally of two types – personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information.

Personally identifiable information comprises any information that can help us identify or locate an individual, including, without limitation, an individual’s name, address, e-mail address, telephone number and credit card number. Personally identifiable information does not include publicly available information that is lawfully made available to the general public from federal, state or local government records.

Non-personally identifiable information comprises information that does not by itself identify an individual. This information generally includes anonymous information about an individual’s use of the Website that includes, among other things, information concerning date and time of visit, the pages of the Website visited, path through the Website, IP address, the type of browser and operating system used.

##### HOW DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION? AND WHY?

######  General 

We do not collect personally identifiable information, except when you specifically and knowingly disclose such information. This information is generally collected when you order our products or services, register your products on the Website, fill out surveys, enter promotional events (including competitions), correspond with us, discuss a service issue on the phone with an associate, sign up to receive Kingston product and service updates or when we meet with you at meetings or events. If you disclose your personal information, we will only store and use such information that we need to meet your requests and our legitimate business objectives, including, where you have consented, providing you with information about products and services that we consider may be of interest to you. We primarily use your personal information to provide you an improved and customized online experience and service. We may use this information for marketing purposes.

######  Product Purchases 

When purchasing through the Website, we employ a registration process which requires that you provide us with your first and last name, billing and shipping information (which includes your home or other physical address, the name of your city or town, your telephone number, your e-mail address or other personal contact information). If you choose not to provide your personal contact information at the point of collection, you will not be able to purchase products through the Website.

######  Product Registration 

When you register we may ask for your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, type of product, serial number, and date of purchase or other product-identifying information. If you choose not to provide this information, you will not be able to register products on the Website; however, you may continue to use the products.

######  Personal Contact Information 

We use your contact information to complete and support your purchases from us, to facilitate and improve your use of the Website, to communicate with you (including sending marketing communications) and to comply with any requirements of law. We also use this information to respond to any questions you might have and to provide you with information about specials offered through the Website. This information may be disclosed to our staff and to third parties involved in the completion of your transaction, the delivery of your order or the support of your use of the Website.

######  Credit Card Information 

When you order any product through our Website or at a Tradeshow or request an RMA (Returned Merchandise Authorization) on our Website, you may be redirected to a third-party payment gateway service to provide your credit card information including the credit card number, card security code (also called CVV2, CVC2, CID code), the expiration date and the billing address. The third-party payment gateway service is fully compliant with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) for payment processing.

######  Online Surveys 

In order to improve our products and services, we may use your personal information to send you online surveys. These surveys help us to know more about your experience with our products and services. Your responses to these surveys are treated as confidential information. If you do not wish to participate in a survey, you may simply decline when asked. You may also choose to opt-out from participating in any future surveys. If you do so, we will not send you any survey requests in the future.

######  Product Updates and Promotional E-mails 

We regularly send product updates and promotional e-mails as a service to our existing customers, and to individuals who have registered or consented to receive such updates and emails. We will use your personal information to send you newsletters and e-mails periodically listing current specials, promotions and deals only if you elect to receive these e-mails. If you have elected to receive these e-mails and wish to discontinue receiving them in the future, please follow the opt-out instructions provided on the e-mails or log into your account on the Website and follow the instructions to make the appropriate changes.

######  Correspondence 

If you contact us by telephone, e-mail, fax or letter with feedback, comments, questions or for any other reason, we may keep a record of that correspondence and collect your personal information to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.

##### HOW DO WE COLLECT YOUR NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION? AND WHY?

######  General 

We automatically collect certain non-personally identifiable information each time you visit the Website. We may use cookies, tags, server logs and other technology to acquire or store this information. We collect this anonymous information so that we may better understand how people are using the Website and to improve the overall quality of our users’ online experience.

######  Cookies 

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit our Website. For information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, please read our [Cookie Policy](http://www.kingston.com/us/company/cookie_policy).

######  Log Files 

Log files record a range of variables related to a visitor’s time on the Website. This includes, but is not limited to: IP addresses, browser versions and types, internet service providers, pages visited, entry/exit pages, referring sites, platform types, demographic information, connection speed, etc. We use this information to understand how our visitors are using the Website and to discover how we might modify the site to better serve our customers. This information is gathered automatically when you visit the Website and is not personally identifiable.

######  Navigational Data 

As you browse the Website and third party sites, we may gather navigational data that shows what pages are visited and how long various features are used. This information will not reveal your identity or be linked to you personally. We use this information to facilitate and improve the Website; to comply with any requirements of law; to serve, or have a third party serve specialized or relevant advertising content and/or recommendations to you on the Website and third party sites; and for our internal purposes. We may from time to time supply the owners or operators of third party sites with information relating to the number of users linking to the Website from their sites. You cannot be identified from this information.

######  IP Addresses and System Specifications 

When you access the Website, our servers may record your IP address. We may use IP addresses for system administration and troubleshooting, ensuring user compliance with our terms of service, investigating security breaches and compiling anonymous non-personal information such as how many users visited the Website.

##### HOW DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT?

######  General 

Personal information which we collect for a particular purpose will only be saved and used for that purpose, unless you have agreed to allow us to use it for some other purpose, as described in this Privacy Policy. We sometimes share non-personal information with third parties about our user base, but that information does not include any personally identifiable information. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, we do not trade, share, rent, sell or give away information concerning you to third parties.

######  Our Affiliates 

We may share your personally identifiable information with legal entities that are directly or indirectly controlled by us or who share common control with us. These affiliates may use your personally identifiable information only in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

######  Our Service Providers and Strategic Partners 

We may disclose your personally identifiable information to our service providers and strategic partners. For instance (without limitation) we will disclose your credit card information to our financial service providers and banks for processing and your name and address to the delivery service we use to deliver products you purchase on the Website. These third party service providers and partners will have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but may not use it for other purposes.

######  Enforcement 

We may disclose your personally identifiable information or otherwise use such information to communicate with you if required or permitted to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (i) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process or any governmental request; (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of Kingston and its affiliates, licensors or licensees; (iii) enforce our applicable service agreements; or (iv) protect the personal safety or interests of Kingston’s employees and consultants, other users of the Website, or members of the public in urgent circumstances. We may also disclose any of your personal information to law enforcement or other appropriate third parties in connection with criminal investigations, investigation of fraud, infringement of intellectual property rights, or other suspected illegal activities, or as otherwise may be required by applicable law, or, as we deem necessary in our sole discretion, in order to protect the legitimate legal and business interests of Kingston.

######  Aggregated General Information 

We may share aggregated general information about the Website with our corporate partners, investors, advertisers or others. Aggregate general information includes without limitation the number of users of the Website, revenue including payments by the users, usage statistics and user feedback. Aggregated general information does not include any personally identifying information that could be used to contact or identify you.

######  Change of Control 

In the event that another company acquires all or substantially all of the assets related to the Website, or if we experience some other change of control event such as merger, insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, we reserve the right to include any or all user-related information among the assets transferred to the acquiring company. We cannot guarantee that any entity receiving such information in connection with any of these transactions will comply with all the terms of this policy.

##### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

The Website complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and all other applicable laws and regulations protecting children’s privacy on the Internet. We do not allow persons under 18 years of age to create user accounts.

Therefore, except as may be required by law, the Website does not knowingly collect, maintain, or disclose any personal information from children under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, please do not: (i) create or attempt to create an account on the Website, (ii) sign up for any subscription service, or (iii) buy anything through the Website.

##### INFORMATION FOR PARENTS/GUARDIANS

As a parent or guardian you can request Kingston to remove personal information pertaining to your child that was submitted without your consent or by misrepresenting his or her age. At your request, we will take reasonable steps to remove such information from our database.

All such requests should include the same user name, password and e-mail address that your child submitted and should be sent to sales@kingston.com.

##### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, stored in, processed in or accessed from countries whose laws provide varied levels of protection, including levels lower than those provided in your own country.

By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing, processing or accessing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

##### SECURITY

Kingston takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to, or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of, users’ information. We restrict access to your personally identifying information to employees who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our products, services and the Website. Our servers are protected by firewalls and are physically located in secure data facilities to further increase security.

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for mutual authentication, data encryption and data integrity. While no computer is 100% safe from outside attacks, we believe that the steps we have taken to protect your personal information drastically reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of information involved.

##### INTEGRITY

During the online account registration process, you can review, change or remove any information you have submitted. Our goal is to ensure that our information about you is as accurate as possible and encourage you to promptly update your information if it changes. You may, at any time, access your information to update, modify or delete any inaccuracies by accessing your account through the Website.

You may also request that we remove your account information from our databases. We will endeavor to remove as much information as legally allowable. However, as we generally keep information related to past transactions for our records, we may not be able to completely remove all of your information.

##### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your information) if we intend to use your information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your information. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [sales@kingston.com](mailto:sales@kingston.com). Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties.

If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites.  If you wish to access or update personal information held about you, or to make any enquiries about the processing of personal information, please contact us at [sales@kingston.com](mailto:sales@kingston.com). Any access request may be subject to an administration fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

##### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

Kingston complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Kingston has certified that it adheres to the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, recourse, enforcement and liability, and dispute resolution. To learn more about the Privacy Shield, please visit <http://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Kingston commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals in the European Union (EU) with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact Kingston at:   
Kingston Technology Company, Inc.   
Attention: Operational Compliance  
17600 Newhope Street  
Fountain Valley, CA. 92708 USA

Kingston has further committed to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact the EU DPAs for more information or to file a complaint. The services of EU DPAs are provided at no cost to you. To learn more about the Kingston Privacy Shield policy, please visit <http://www.kingston.com/us/company/privacyshield>.

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of Personal Data should be directed to Kingston at the address given above. Kingston will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding the use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy within 45 days of receiving a complaint.

Kingston is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) with regard to Kingston’s compliance with the Privacy Shield.

Kingston will obtain assurances from its Agents that they will safeguard Personal Data consistent with this policy. If Kingston has knowledge that an Agent is using or disclosing Personal Data in a manner contrary to this policy, Kingston will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.

Under certain circumstances, Kingston may remain liable for the acts of its third-party agents or service providers who perform services on its behalf for their handling of personal data that Kingston transfers to them.

Under certain circumstances, Kingston may be required to disclose your personal data in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain circumstances, you may have the option to select binding arbitration for the resolution of your complaint.

##### CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

We may change our policy at any time by posting a new version of it on the Website. We encourage you to check the Website regularly for information about revisions to this Privacy Policy. In the event that we change our Privacy Policy, such changes will affect all of the information we collect after any such change. If you object to the change to our Privacy Policy, then you must contact us in writing regarding your objection.

For the purpose of the UK Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is Kingston Technology Europe Co LLP, Kingston Digital Europe Co LLP or both, as the context so requires. Both companies are located at Kingston Court, Brooklands Close, Sunbury on Thames, Middlesex, TW16 7EP, UK.

##### QUESTIONS AND COMMENTS

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at
